Preliminary Guide to the Anita Shreve Papers, 1982-2002
Anita Shreve papers 1982-2002
Shreve, Anita
14.0 Linear Feet 721 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Freelance journalist and writer in the United States.
Galley proofs, typescripts, drafts, and notes for Shreve's work. Also includes files from her literary agent.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Anita Shreve Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2002, 2003, and 2011.
Biographical Note
American freelance journalist and writer (1986-present). Born 1946. Formerly deputy director of Viva magazine; affiliated with US and Newsweek. Winner of the O. Henry Award.
Collection Overview
Collection (Accession 2002-0120) (21 items, 2.4 lin. ft.; dated 1987-2001) comprises primarily page and galley proofs, as well as typescripts for six of Shreve's novels and nonfiction books (1987-2001). The books include The Last Time They Met, Fortune's Rocks, Strange Fits of Passion, The Weight of Water, Remaking Motherhood, and Resistance.
Addition (Accession 2002-0136) (300 items; 10.80 lin. ft.; dated [ca. 1989]-2002) consists primarily of typescript and hand-written drafts, proofs, hand-written notes, and research for novels by Shreve ([ca. 1989]-2002), including Fortune's Rocks, The Pilot's Wife, Sea Glass, and The Weight of Water. Addition also includes editor and publisher correspondence, contracts, and royalty statements (1992-1993).
Addition (Accession 2003-0222) (3 items; 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 2002-2003) consists of the typescript (with editing marks) and master proof of Shreve's novel All He Ever Wanted (2003), along with a piece of correspondence from the publisher.
Addition (Accession 2011-0059) (400 items; 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 1982-1995) contains files about Shreve kept by Virginia Barber, her literary agent. Includes correspondence between them as well as Barber's correspondence and other materials promoting Shreve's work.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Shreve, Anita
American literature -- 20th century
Authors, American -- 20th century
Authors, American -- 20th century -- Correspondence.
Galley proofs
Proofs
Barber, Virginia
Literary agents -- Correspondence
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2002-0120
  - Page and galley proofs for The Last Time They Met,2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Page and galley proofs for Fortune's Rocks,1999-2000
  - Page and galley proofs for Fortune's Rocks,1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Three sets of page proofs for Strange Fits of Passion,1991
  - Little, Brown catalog, 2001; Two publicity items for The Last Time They Met and Fortune's Rocks
  - Typed draft for Remaking Motherhood,1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Page and galley proofs for Resistance,1995-1996
  - Page and two galley proofs for The Weight of Water,1997
  - Page and two galley proofs for The Weight of Water,1997 (Box 4)
  - Page proofs for Strange Fits of Passion,1991
- Accession 2002-0136
  - Notes and drafts of The Pilot's Wife,1996-1997 and undated (Box 1-3)
  - Drafts of The Weight of Water, undated (Box 3)
  - Proofs of The Pilot's Wife, undated (Box 4)
  - Proof and copyedited manuscript of The Last Time They Met,2000
  - Proofs, drafts, notes, and research for Sea Glass,2002 (Box 5-7)
  - Proofs of The Weight of Water,1996 (Box 8)
  - Drafts, proofs, and notes for Sea Glass, [ca. 2000]
  - Drafts and notes for Sea Glass, [ca. 2000] (Box 9-11)
  - Drafts and notes for Eden Close, undated (Box 12)
  - Drafts and notes for Strange Fits of Passion, undated
  - Contracts correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 13)
  - Notes and research, undated
  - Contracts and royalty statements, 1992-1993
  - Notes, research, and drafts of The Weight of Water,[ca. 1995] (Box 14-15)
  - Drafts of The Weight of Water,[ca. 1995] (Box 16)
  - Drafts and research for Fortune's Rocks, undated
  - Drafts of Fortune's Rocks, undated (Box 17)
  - Drafts of Fortune's Rocks, undated (Box 18)
  - Drafts of Where or When, undated
- Accession (2003-0222), 2002-2003, (1 box)
  Addition (2003-0222) (3 items, 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 2002-2003) consists of the typescript (with editing marks) and master proof of Shreve's novel All He Ever Wanted (2003), along with a piece of correspondence from the publisher.
  - All He Ever Wanted typescript (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
- Accession (2011-0059), 1982-1995, (1 box)
  Addition (Accession 2011-0059) (400 items; 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 1982-1995) contains files about Shreve kept by Virginia Barber, her literary agent. Includes correspondence between them as well as Barber's correspondence and other materials promoting Shreve's work. Arranged chronologically.
  - Files, 1982-1995 (Box 1)